Guide to the Clarence Stein papers, 1905-1983.
Stein, Clarence papers
- Series VI. Correspondence Files
  - Carlson, Eric (Chief,Housing Section, Center for Housing, Building and Planning, United Nations, N.Y., Foundation for Cooperative Housing, Inc., Inter-American Housing and Planning Center, Assoc. Editor, "The American City") (Box 14, Folder 33)
    Roger Willcox, Roy Lubove
    1951-1958, 1960-1965, 1967-1968
    correspondence, reports, notes, press release, article
  - Christmas: Cards, Letters, Gifts (Box 14, Folder 34)
    1951-1968
    notes, correspondence
  - Henry Churchill (Box 14, Folder 35)
    1954-1955, 1961-1962
  - C.H.P.C.: Planned Development Committee [Citizen's Housing and Planning Council] (Box 14, Folder 36)
    1948, 1965
    article, listing
  - Citizen's Housing Council -- Gen. Corres. (Box 14, Folder 37)
    Richard Ravith (Pres., CH & PC), Ira S. Robbin (Exec. VP), Harold S. Buttenheim (Pres.)
    1941, 1947-1948, 1950-1951, 1957, 1970
    correspondence, memos, newsletters, amendments and by-laws, maps, photographs, articles
  - Citizens' Housing Council/Minutes Post-War Planning Comm. (Box 14, Folder 38)
    Ralph Walker, Carl Stein
    1951, 1942-1943
    Citizens Union Committee on City Planning
    report, correspondence, minutes, memos
  - Citizens' Union (see also Columbus Circle) (Box 14, Folder 39)
    1951, 1972
    membership card, advertisement
  - Columbia University -- Dean Telfer (Box 14, Folder 40)
    listing of architect-planners, correspondence
  - Columbia University School of Architecture (Box 14, Folder 41)
    Charles R. Colbert (Dean), Harry A. Anthony (Planning and Housing Division, J. Marshal Miller (Planning and Housing Division)
    1947-1948, 1956-1957, 1961-1963, 1967
    correspondence, outline, report, notes, program
  - Columbia Univ. Urban Planning Seminar (Box 14, Folder 42)
    Dean Charles Colbert, Architecture, Albert Mayer, Stanley Tankel (Planning Director, Regional Plan Assoc. )
    1961-1963
    Regional Plan Association, Inc.
    chart, notes, correspondence, outlines, clipping
  - Cornell (Finch) (Box 14, Folder 43)
    Herbert Finch (Curator and Archivist, C.U.)
    1967-1968, 1970-1972
  - Cosmos Club (CSS Admission as Member) (Box 14, Folder 44)
    articles of incorporation and by-laws
    Ben ton MacKaye
    1954, 1959, 1961, 1966
    pamphlets, list of members
  - Costume Art, Institute of (Box 14, Folder 45)
    Polaire Weissman (Director), Mary Reban (Secretary)
    1944, 1948, 1950, 1956, 1958-1959, 1964
    correspondence, articles, minutes, notes, clippings, memo
  - D -- General incl. Dentist (Box 14, Folder 46)
    Tom Desmond (Chairman, Committee on Affairs of Cities, N.Y. Senate), Henry Dreyfuss
    1948, 1955-1957, 1962-1963, 1965
  - Data On Returned Drawings c. Alexander M. Bing, Hardie Phillip (Box 14, Folder 47)
    1946, undated
    Phipps Houses, Inc., Hillside Housing Corp.
    lists, correspondence
  - Denmark Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 48)
    Steen Eiler Rasmussen, Ole Thomassen, Peter Bredsdorffs
    1950-1951, 1953-1958, 1960, 1962-1967
  - Vernon and Betty DeMars (Box 14, Folder 49)
    1947, 1950-1953, 1955, 1958, 1960-1961, 1963-1964, 1967-1970
    correspondence, articles, clippings, photographs, resume
  - Dept. of Urban and Regional Development (Box 14, Folder 50)
    proposed government administration department
    outline notes
  - E -- General (Box 14, Folder 51)
    Ralph Eberlin (Civil Engineer), Simon Eisner, John L. Egan (Comm., Public Housing Administration)
    1948-1949, 1953, 1961-1964, 1966-1968
    N.Y. Society for Ethical Culture
  - English, correspondence: Stephenson, Gordon (see other under T.N.T. for Am. & T.P.R.) (Box 14, Folder 52)
    Stephenson, Gordon
    1951, 1953-1965, 1967-1970
    Town and Regional Planning, School of Architecture, Univ. of Toronto
  - English Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 53)
    Frederick J. Osborn, Wyndham Thomas (Gen. Manager, Peterborough Dev. Corp., and Town & Country Planning Assoc. ), Arthur Ling, Jane Unwin (daughter-in-law of Ray Unwin), Lewis Mumford, Dame Evelyn Sharp, Robert Alexander, Paul Ritter, Percy Johnson-Marshal (Univ. of Edinburgh), William Holford, S. Jellicoe
    1950-1953, 1955-1970
    Peterborough Development Corp., Town & Country Planning Assoc., Town Planning Review
    notes, correspondence, clipping
  - English Correspondence;, Osborn, Sir Frederic J. (Incl. New Towns correspondence) American New Towns (Box 14, Folder 54)
    Paul Opperman, Catherine B. Wurster
    1945, 1947-1948, 1950-1953, 1955, 1959-1970
    International Organization for World Town Planning Day, Town and Country Planning, American Institute of Planners
    correspondence, pamphlets, photo, clipping, notes, itineraries, lists
  - English correspondence. TPR -- Correspondence [Town Planning Review] (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Myles Wright (Editor), Gordon Stephenson
    1952-1955
  - English correspondence. TPR -- Foundation, support of (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Myles Wright (Editor, TPR, Prof., Design, Univ. of Liverpool), Douglas W. Orr (Pres., AAF), J. Frazier Smith (AAF)
    1950, 1953, 1955, 1964
    University of Liverpool, American Institute of Architects, American Architecture Foundation, Inc.
    correspondence, notes, (Committee) listing, memos, announcements
  - F (Carl Feiss included) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Carl Feiss, F.J. Osbom, James Felt (Chairman, Planning Commission, N.Y.C.), Frederic R. Stevenson
    1951, 1955-1961, 1963-1968, 1970
    Banking and Currency Committee, U.S. House of Representatives, Foundation For Cooperative Housing, Ethical Culture Society
    correspondence, statement, reports, notes
  - Finland (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Heikki von Hertzen
    Finnish-American Chamber of Commerce
    correspondence, newsletter
  - Foundations FCH (Services Inc.) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    1969 Housing and Urban Redevelopment Act
    Roger Willcox (Pres., R&D, FCH), Winslow Carlton (Chairman, Board of Trustees, FCH), Wallace Campbell (Pres., FCH), David L. Krool
    1953, 1966, 1968-1970
    Foundation for Cooperative Housing, Inc., Cooperative League of the USA, International Cooperative Housing Development Assoc.
    correspondence, memo, reports, minutes, clipping, statements, resolution, roster, promissory note
  - France (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Julian C. Levi
    drawing, business cards, notes, clipping
  - G -- General (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Maureen and Ernest Grunsfelt, Victor Gruen
    1948-1960, 1963-1968, 1970
  - Germany -- Correspondence [not all in English.] (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Ernst May, Ing. Hermann Hucker
    1952, 1955, 1957, 1959-1960, 1963
  - Greece --Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Gutheim, Fritz (includes Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    metropolitan open spaces
    1950-1952, 1960-1961, 1963-1964, 1967-1968
    Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies
    correspondence, pamphlet, report, outlines, papers
  - H -- General (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Museum of Man, San Diego, California
    Arthur C. Holden, Samuel W. Hand, Robert M. Hopkins, Heikki von Hertzen
    1950, 1954, 1958-1970
    articles, correspondence, drawing, plan
  - Hawaii State Plan (Box 15, Folder 12)
    1959, 1962
    correspondence, pamphlets, notes
  - Holland (Box 15, Folder 13)
    criticism of Henry Wright's last building
    (Prof.) Wieger Bruin
    1949, 1958-1960, 1963-1964
    correspondence, lists
  - Holland (Box 15, Folder 14)
    town and regional planning
    1950, 1955, 1957-1958
    articles, pamphlets, postcards, reports, maps
  - I -- General, incl. Lists of Insurance (Box 15, Folder 15)
    1949-1950, 1952-1953, 1963, 1970, 1972
    International Federation for Housing and Town Planning, IBEC Housing Corporation, Governmental Affairs Institute
    correspondence, articles, pamphlet
  - Information Requested (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Iran -- 1959 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Catherine Bauer, Benjamin Kizer
    1958-1960, 1962, 1964
    lists, notes, photographs, correspondence, plans, slides
  - Iran: Isphahan: Terence O'Donnell Letter Oct. 22/59 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    notes and letter
  - Israel: 1959 Trip and Later (Box 15, Folder 19)
    (Prof.) Al. Mansfeld, Karl Belsar, Artur Glikson, Arieh Sharon
    1959-1965, 1967, 1969-1970
    Ministry of Housing, Israel
    articles, notes, correspondence, photographs, pamphlets, plans
  - Italy-correspondence (Box 15, Folder 20)
    requests for Radburn plans
    1953, 1957, 1959
  - J (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Frank B. Jordan, Jr. (Hillside Housing Corp.)
    1949-1950, 1952, 1955
  - K -- General (Box 15, Folder 22)
    David L. Krooth (Chairman, Committee on Housing and Urban Renewal, American Bar Association), Henry Klaber
    1947-1963, 1965-1969
    correspondence, articles, drawings
  - B. Kizer (Box 15, Folder 23)
    Benjamin Kizer (lawyer, Spokane, Washington)
    1947-1968
    correspondence, clipping
  - General (Box 15, Folder 24)
    Roy Lubove (University of Pittsburgh), David Lilienthal, Robert M. Lillibridge (Chicago Land Clearance Commission)
    1953-1969
  - Lapping, Mark B. (Thesis On Stein and F.L. Wright, 1969) (Box 15, Folder 25)
    1969
  - Liang, Ssu-Ch'Eng (Box 15, Folder 26)
    1947-1948, 1958
  - Library (Box 15, Folder 27)
    C.S. Stein's library
    1935, undated
    listing, memos, correspondence, pamphlet
  - M General (Box 15, Folder 28)
    Arthur Mayer, Martin Meyerson (Dean, University of California, Berkeley, College of Environmental Design
    1947-1951, 1955-1956, 1958-1963, 1966-1968
    correspondence, reports, pamphlets, clipping
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. through 1967 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    flood control, conservation
    Lewis Mumford, Col. Theodore Roosevelt, Ass't Secretary of the Navy
    1924, 1928-1930, 1939-1942, 1948-1956
    The Wilderness Society
    correspondence, clippings, program, articles, memos, drafts
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. through 1967 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    correspondence, resolutions
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. through 1967 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    1961, 1963
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. through 1967 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    Geotechnics
    Donald Jackson (Editor, Univ. of Illinois Pres Lewis Mumford, Karl Belsar
    1964-1965
    correspondence, clipping, articles, memo, drawings
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. through 1967 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    Lewis Mumford, Donald Jackson (Editor, Univ. of Illinois Press)
    1966
    correspondence, notes, reprints, clippings
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. through 1967 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    correspondence, memo, clipping
  - Benton MacKaye corresp. 1968 on (Box 15, Folder 35)
    1968-1971
    correspondence, clippings, articles, memo
  - May: Ernst. Prospective Visit to U.S. (Box 15, Folder 36)
    Dorothy Gazzolo (Assoc. Dir., National Assn. of Housing and Redevelopment Officials), Roger Willcox
    1958-1959, 1965
    H.S.B. Swedich Housing Group
    correspondence, itinerary
  - Mayer, Albert: General Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 37)
    Ralph Walker, Carl Feiss, McKim Norton
    1949, 1952, 1954-1959, undated
    speech, correspondence, notes, clippings, reports
  - Mayer, Albert: General Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 38)
    Simon Breines, Edmund T. Ames (District of Kitimat), Chester Bowles
    1960-1963
    correspondence, notes, drafts, outlines
  - Mayer, Albert: General Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 39)
    Urgent Future
    1964-1967
    notes, correspondence, reprints, memo
  - Mayer, Albert: General Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 40)
    community environment and aging
    George H. Favre (Chief,News Bureau, The Christian Science Monitor)
    1968-1970
    correspondence, notes, articles, memo, clippings, photographs, speech
  - Me -- General (Box 15, Folder 41)
    Charles McDonald, Robert. Weaver (Adm., Housing and Home Finance Agency)
    1950-1953, 1957, 1961-1965
    correspondence, clipping, newsletters, drawing
  - Marie McGuire (Box 15, Folder 42)
    Robert C. Weaver (Adm., Housing and Home Finance Agency)
    1963-1964, 1966-1967
    press release, correspondence, notes, memo
  - METCOP [Metropolitan Committee on Planning] (Box 15, Folder 43)
    Walter Truslow, Jr. (Chairman, State Planning Committee ), Henry Fagin
    1949-1950, 1955, 1958
    memos, correspondence, program
  - Mexico [not all in English] (Box 15, Folder 44)
    Radburn-type Mexican housing
    Simon Eisner
    1956, 1958, 1960
    addresses, correspondence, notes, lists, voucher
  - Milwaukee Development (Box 15, Folder 45)
    Vincent Lung (Planning Director), Walter E. Kroening (Community Manager, Greendale, Wisc.)
    1949, 1963
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 16, Folder 1)
    1961-1964, 1966-1970
    The Committee of the Planning Professions To End the War in Vietnam
    clipping, correspondence, speech, press leases, notes
  - Lewis Mumford (Box 16, Folder 2)
    to Lewis Mumford
    1960-1970
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 16, Folder 3)
    letters from Stein to Mumford
    1946-1959
    notes, correspondence, articles
  - Mumford, Lewis letters 1947 to 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    letters from Mumford to Stein
    1966-1971
    correspondence, plan
  - Mumford, Lewis letters 1947 to 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    1957-1965
    correspondence, clipping, article
  - Mumford, Lewis Letters 1947 to 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    1946-1956
  - N -- General (Box 16, Folder 7)
    1954, 1960, 1966
    New York League for the Hard of Hearing, Stein Fund
  - National Housing Conf. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    David L. Krooth (Chairman of the Legislative Committee of the National Housing Conference), Lee Johnson
    1947-1951, 1964-1965
    correspondence, notes, memos, newsletter, bulletin
  - Newark Group N.T. Policy (Box 16, Folder 9)
    new towns in the U.S.
    Carl Feiss, Dennis O' Harrow, Albert Mayer, Paul Opperman
    1964
  - New Towns (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Astrid and Donald Monson
    1964, 1966
    pamphlet, map, report, correspondence
  - N.Y.C. -- New Charter. Planned Development (Box 16, Folder 11)
    John T. Cahill (Chairman, Charter Revision Commission), James Felt (NYS Planning Commission)
    American Institute of Architects, NYS --Moore-- Committee,NYS Planning Commission
    notes, correspondence, minutes, outlines, proposals, article
  - North Carolina (Box 16, Folder 12)
    F. Stuart Chapin, Jr., John A. Parker (Head, Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Univ. of N.C. ), Matthew Nowicki, Albert Mayer
    1949-1952, 1959
    Dept. of City and Regional Planning, Univ. of N.C., School of Design, North Carolina State College
    correspondence, map, program, catalogues, research analysis, clippings, reprints
  - Regional Plan & Development Dept.-- Uni of NC (Box 16, Folder 13)
    1950
    programs, conferences, correspondence
  - Matthew Nowicki (Box 16, Folder 14)
    1948-1950, 1952, 1954, 1959, 1961
    articles, correspondence, notes
  - O -- General (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Paul Oehser, Dennis O'Harrow (Exec. Dir., American Society of Planning Officials)
    1952, 1961-1964
  - Oppermann, Paul (Box 16, Folder 16)
    1952-1953, 1955-1958, 1961-1963
    correspondence, newsletter, memo
  - P -- General (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Hardie Phillip, Hugh Pomeroy (Director, Westchester County Dept. of Planning), Roy Potter (Planning Director, Fremont, California), Raphael Pollock (Chief of Mission OAS)
    1948-1951, 1955, 1957, 1959-1968
    Embassy of Pakistan, Organization of American States
    correspondence, photographs, report, resolution, pamphlet, plans, newsletter, map, drawing
  - Public Housing Administration (Marie McGuire) (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - R -- General (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Isadore Rosenfield, Ira Robbins, Sam Ratensky, Blake McKelvey
    1954-1961, 1963-1970
    Radburn
    article, correspondence, notes, program, outline:
  - Reg. & Town Planning (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Ritter, Paul (on Radburn Idea), etc. [not all in English] (Box 16, Folder 21)
    1959-1961, 1963
  - S -- General (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Gordon Stephenson, Carl Stein, S.J. Schulman, Chloethiel Woodward Smith
    1926-1931, 1952, 1955-1964, 1967, 1969-1970
    Snag Club, American New Towns Committee
    correspondence, articles, lists, notes, memo, resume
  - Scotland--Housing (Box 16, Folder 23)
    1950, 1954
  - Slyton, Wm. Commissioner of Urban Renewal Administration (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Urban Renewal Administration, Housing and Home Finance Agency
  - New Towns for America -- for Snag Club -- May 1964 Preparatory Material (Box 16, Folder 25)
    notes, outline, notice, correspondence, revisions
  - South America 1957 [not all in English] (Box 16, Folder 26)
    Eric Carlson (Inter- American Housing Center), Hector Velarde
    1953, 1955, 1957, 1959
    correspondence, notes, articles, addresses
  - Stockholm Notes 1954 Vivist (Box 16, Folder 27)
    J.H. Martin, Yngve Larsson
    1952-1954, 1960
    correspondence, map, drawing, notes
  - Sweden Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 28)
    expanded towns, Farsta
    Yngve and Elin Larsson, Goren Sidenbladh, Sven Markelios, Lawrence M. Orton (CNYC Planning Commission)
    1949-1952, 1954, 1957-1958, 1960-1962, 1964-1965
    notes, correspondence, lists, article, postcards, map
  - Sweden -- Yngve Larsson (Box 16, Folder 29)
    1949-1952, 1954-1955, 1957-1963, 1966-1969
  - Stockholm, Sweden. J. H. Martin (Box 16, Folder 30)
    1952-1954, 1956, 1958, 1960-1961
    Stockholms Stads Fastighetskonto
    memos, article, correspondence
  - Sweden: Goran Sidenbladh (Box 16, Folder 31)
    1953-1957, 1959-1961, 1964-1965, 1966-1967
    Stockholms Stads Stadsbyggnadskontor
  - Swedish Architecture Exhibition Museum of Modern Art (Box 16, Folder 32)
    Catherine Bauer, Yngve Larsson, Sven Markalius
    1950, 1952
  - T -- General (Box 16, Folder 33)
    Lawrence Tucker (Cincinnati Community Development Co. )
    1949-1951, 1956-1957, 1960, 1963-1964
    correspondence, memos
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 16, Folder 34)
    Aubrey J. Wagner (Chairman TVA)
    1962-1963, o967, 1969-1970
    correspondence, pamphlet, clipping, memo
  - Tennessee Valley Authority Lilienthal & Clarence Stein Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 35)
    Aubrey J. Wagner, David E. Lilienthal (Chairman, TVA)
    1933, 1941, 1944-1945, 1951, 1958, 1964, 1967-1968
    annual reports, news releases, correspondence, photographs, clippings, reviews, articles
  - Kitimat in T.P.R. & Arch. Forum Future of T.P.R., 1951 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    Gordon Stephenson, Julian Whittlesey, Albert Mayer
    1953-1962
    clippings, correspondence, notes, outline, programs, maps
  - Tsing Hua University, Peiping also Mei -- Pres. of National Tsing Hua University (Box 16, Folder 37)
    1946-1947
    Chelsea Fireproof Storage Warehouse, Inc.
    correspondence, invoices, list, memo
  - Travel: 1956 CSS, AMS (Box 16, Folder 38)
    reservations, Egypt
  - U: General (Box 16, Folder 39)
    1951, 1962, 1970
  - Raymond Unwin (Box 16, Folder 40)
    Raymond Unwin memorial service
    Jane Unwin, Carl Feiss, Frederic J. Osborn, Lewis Mumford
    1946, 1953, 1957, 1960, 1963, 1965-1967, undated
    correspondence, notes, article, photograph, lists
  - V (Box 16, Folder 41)
    Henry B. van Loon, Gretchen Van Tassel, Francis Violich (Chairman, City and Regional Planning Dept., Univ. of California, Berkeley
    1954, 1957-1958, 1960-1962, 1964
  - W -- General File (Box 16, Folder 42)
    Joseph Watterson (Chief, Historic Architect, Div. National Park Service, US Dept. of Interior), William W. Wurster (Dean, College of Architecture,- Univ. of Berkeley), Dr. Robert Weaver
    1936, 1949, 1956-1958, 1960-1964, 1966-1969, 1971
    article, correspondence, notes
  - "The City" (Box 16, Folder 43)
    Ralph Walker
    correspondence, note, paper
  - Wank, Roland (Box 16, Folder 44)
    1941, 1944, 1963
    Tennessee Valley Authority
    correspondence, resume
  - Washington Comm. Dev. Trust (Eric Carlson, Gutheim). Also Proposal For a Demonstration Program (Catherine Bauer, Exec. U.C.B.) [Berkeley in Urban Development I (Box 16, Folder 45)
    Center for Planning arid Development Research (Univ. of California, Berkeley), Washington Community Development Trust
    prospectus, notes, proposal
  - Washington University Planning Department (Box 16, Folder 46)
    1956, 1962
  - Welfare Island (Box 16, Folder 47)
    development of Welfare Island
    Victor Gruen (Architect), Robert F. Wagner (May or N.Y.), C. McKim Norton (RPA, Inc.), Albert Mayer
    Regional Plan Assoc., AIA Committee of Urban Design, Metropolitan Committee on Planning
    press releases, article, clippings, notes, correspondence, minutes
  - Whittlesey, Julian (Box 16, Folder 48)
    Kitimat profile
    Arieh Sharon, Charles Aschev, Albert Mayer
    1950-1952, 1954, 1957, 1959, 1963, 1968-1969
  - Willcox, Roger (Box 16, Folder 49)
    Peppertree Town Houses
    Anita Willcox
    1946, 1950-1951, 1953-1954, 1957-1958, 1961-1966, 1968-1969
    correspondence, outline, listing, notes, resumes
  - Wilson, Lewis (Box 16, Folder 50)
    1948-1951, 1954-1957
    correspondence, report, clipping
  - Wolff, Werner (Box 16, Folder 51)
    1960-1972
    correspondence, articles, photographs
  - Henry Wright (Box 16, Folder 52)
    Eleanor Wright
    1931, 1936, 1967
    Committee on Design, President's Conference on Home Building and Ownership
    biographical material, correspondence, bulletins, memos
  - William W. Wurster (Box 16, Folder 53)
    1954-1955, 1958, 1960, 1967-1969
    correspondence, resume, photographs, plans
  - XYZ (Box 16, Folder 54)
    1950-1952, 1955, 1957, 1961, 1963,
  - Lewis Mumford-C. S. Stein correspondence, 1923-1943 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Lewis Mumford-C. S. Stein correspondence, 1944-1952 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Lewis Mumford-C. S. Stein correspondence, 1954-1972 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Lewis Mumford's correspondence concerning statement of purpose for the Regional Planning Association of America (very brittle) copies for use in folder 1, additional related material, 1925, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from C. S. Stein to his family while he was in Europe traveling and a student at the Ecole des Beaux Arts, Paris. also letters to his mother when she was on vacation, 1903-1911 (Box 29)
  - Copies of correspondence (1st European trip), May-August 1903 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, originals to Stein's mother when she was on vacation, June-July 1904 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (letters from C.S. Stein to his family), June-December 1905 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January-June 1906 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1906 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January-December 1906 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, January-December 1907 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Jan. 1909-Dec. 1 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Jan.--August 1911 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (partial letters) undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Copied excerpts pp. 1-28 1905 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Copied excerpts pp. 29-47 1906 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Copied excerpts pp. 48-72 1907 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Copied excerpts pp. 73-107 1908 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Copied excerpts pp. 110-141 1909-1911 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Contains excerpts from Clarence Stein's letters from 1931 to 1953 edited by Aline MacMahon Stein in 1982
    - Correspondence from C. S. Stein to Goodhue and others 1914-1918 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Misc. correspondence from C. S. Stein (in process) (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. Stein's notes on excerpted material 1976 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Excerpts 1931 & 1932 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Excerpts 1933-1935 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Excerpts 1936, 1938, 1941, 1947, 1948, 1951, 1952, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence from B. G. Goodhue 1916-1918 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence from Ebenezer Howard (photograph of Howard) 1925 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - C. S.S. to Lewis Mumford Sept. 13, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 9)